Do you like drinking coffee?
你喜欢喝咖啡吗？
I certainly do.
我当然喜欢。
In fact you could say I’m an addict because I have to drink a cup every morning to kick-start my day and get my brain working!
事实上，你可以说我是个咖啡成瘾者，因为我每天早上都得喝一杯咖啡来开启新的一天，让我的大脑运转起来！
Latte, cappuccino, espresso – you name it, I‘ll drink it.
拿铁、卡布奇诺、浓缩咖啡——不管什么咖啡，我都喝。
And I’m not alone – it seems like everyone has a coffee cup glued to their hands as they rush to the office.
而且不只是我一个人这样——似乎每个人在冲向办公室的时候手里都紧紧握着一个咖啡杯。
So how would we survive if there was a coffee drought?
那么，如果出现咖啡短缺，我们该如何生存呢？
Well, experts are warning that our favourite caffeine shot could really be under threat.
嗯，专家们警告说，我们最喜欢的含咖啡因饮品确实可能受到威胁。
Our love for coffee could mean that demand outstrips supply.
我们对咖啡的喜爱可能意味着需求超过了供应。
This, of course, could hit us in the pocket but there‘s even worse news – we could face poorer-tasting coffee.
当然，这可能会让我们的钱包受损，但还有更糟糕的消息——我们可能会喝到味道更差的咖啡。
This is the view of scientists at London’s Kew Gardens who are blaming global warming for this possible hot beverage crisis.
这是伦敦邱园的科学家们的观点，他们认为全球变暖是这场可能出现的热饮危机的罪魁祸首。
Demand for coffee has certainly increased as people have become more affluent.
随着人们变得更加富裕，对咖啡的需求肯定是增加了。
Consumption has doubled in the last 35 years.
在过去的35年里，咖啡消费量翻了一番。
Last year 9.5 billion kilos were consumed.
去年，共消耗了95亿公斤的咖啡。
But as we drink more, the areas where coffee is grown is predicted to shrink.
但随着我们喝得更多，预计咖啡种植的地区将会减少。
The International Coffee Organisation says that bean production in South East Asia, for example, will decrease by 70% by 2050.
国际咖啡组织表示，例如，到2050年，东南亚的咖啡豆产量将减少70%。
The BBC spoke to Dr Tim Schilling, director of the World Coffee Research institute, who says: “The supply of high-quality coffee is severely threatened by climate change, diseases and pests, land pressure, and labour shortages - and demand for these coffees is rising every year.”
BBC采访了世界咖啡研究所的所长蒂姆·席林博士，他说：“高品质咖啡的供应受到气候变化、病虫害、土地压力和劳动力短缺的严重威胁，而对这些咖啡的需求却在逐年上升。”
This is a sobering thought for those of us who rely on a caffeine fix everyday but more worrying for people who work in the industry.
对于我们这些每天都依赖咖啡因提神的人来说，这是一个发人深省的想法，但对于咖啡行业的从业者来说，这更令人担忧。
Coffee provides a livelihood for about 16% of Ethiopia‘s population.
咖啡为大约16%的埃塞俄比亚人口提供了生计。
And across the globe, extreme weather events are proving a challenge to coffee growers in places such as Brazil and Vietnam.
而且在全球范围内，极端天气事件给巴西和越南等地的咖啡种植者带来了挑战。
There is some hope.
还是有一些希望的。
Technology is helping to protect the future of coffee such as ’breeding‘ the Arabica bean plants to increase its diversity and making it resistant to climatic changes.
科技正在帮助保护咖啡的未来，比如“培育”阿拉比卡咖啡豆植株，以增加其多样性，并使其适应气候变化。
It’s also possible to relocate the coffee-growing areas — although this sometimes leads to areas being deforested.
重新安置咖啡种植区域也是可能的，尽管这有时会导致一些地区被砍伐森林。
Dr Aaron Davis, coffee researcher at Kew, says: “There is the potential to mitigate some of the negatives and actually increase the coffee-growing area by four and a half times compared with maintaining the status quo.”
邱园的咖啡研究员亚伦·戴维斯博士说：“与维持现状相比，这一做法有可能减轻一些负面影响，并增加4.5倍咖啡种植面积。”
But will this come quick enough before our coffee turns bitter and we look for a cheaper alternative?
但是，在我们的咖啡变得苦涩，我们开始寻找更便宜的替代品之前，这些措施会来得足够快吗？